bridgeport.edu 2019-02-05

# Privacy Policy | University of Bridgeport

## Main navigation

  * Administration
  * Campus Map
  * Employment
  * Firsts and Bests
  * Fast Facts

Image

Privacy Policy

The University of Bridgeport (“UB”) respects and protects the privacy of its website users (“Users”) in accordance with applicable state, federal, and international law.  As such, UB provides the following information to clearly and simply explain how personal information is collected and used.

### 1\. Information Collected

UB collects two general categories of information, as further described below:

**A. Automatically Collected Information**

UB’s website automatically gathers certain information to track User website browsing patterns.  This data – which generally does not contain any personally identifiable information – is used by UB to more fully understand how its website is being used and whether certain website content could be enhanced. This automatically collected     information includes:

  * **Routing information** : the internet address from which the User accessed the UB website, transaction size and referring domain.
  * **Technical Access Information** : basic information about how the User accessed the UB website including date/time, size and browser/system type.
  * **Cookies** : small pieces of data stored on User’s computer while the User is browsing the UB website. Users may refuse the use of cookies through browser settings, but doing so may affect User’s ability to fully access the website.

**B. Personal Information Provided by User**

Users might also provide various types of personal information to UB (through its website) as part of their educational experience, employment, or other participation in the University community. This information can be shared at several different stages of the educational process – prior to admission, as a student, and post-graduation. “Personal information” refers to information related to the identity of a person, including but not limited to:

  * **Contact Information**  such as name, email, address, date of birth, social security and phone number.
  * **Academic Information**  such as schools attended, academic history (courses, testing results, grades), extracurricular interests (athletics, clubs), academic recommendations.
  * **Other Relevant Information**  such as job history; family/personal circumstances; disciplinary and/or criminal history, information regarding health, disability, race and/or national origin.

The following examples illustrate situations in which Users might provide personal information to UB:

  * **Fundraising:  **communications with or outreach from UB regarding development, fundraising, and/or alumni events.
  * **Admissions applications:  **responses to questions in UB admissions process (regarding the topics listed above) and submission related materials.
  * **Athletic Recruitment:  **information provided to a UB coach or contracted recruiting partner regarding the User’s athletic and academic capabilities.
  * **Accessing Electronic Resources and Databases:  **basic name, username, and/or profile information submitted when creating user accounts for various databases and educational resources through the UB network. ** **
  * **Questions about or Communications with UB:  **general inquiries to the University regarding admissions, facilities, academic programs, athletics, and/ or other University functions.

### 2. Basis for Collecting the Personal Information

* * *

UB collects and uses personal information with regard to applicants and students toward the goal of providing quality, post-secondary educational services to undergraduate and graduate students and continuing engagement of alumni and others who support the University’s mission.  Specifically, the University collects personal information in its admissions process (including student-athlete recruitment) to recruit and select candidates who are academically suited for UB, as well as to identify accepted students who would benefit from specific campus services. Information about students is maintained by various departments, including the Registrar, Student Services, Department of Athletics, and University Research, for purposes of supporting and enhancing students’ educational experience, and reporting to federal and state agencies, accreditors and the NCAA. Personal information regarding alumni, donors and other supporters of the University is maintained and used by the Office of University Relations.

### 3\. Retention Period for Personal Information

* * *

Personal information of students is generally retained for a minimum of five (5) years from graduation or the last date of attendance.  Personal information of employees is generally retained for a minimum of seven (7) years from the last date of employment.  However, some information may be permanently retained by UB to properly maintain Users’ academic records (e.g. transcript), as well as to support UB’s related alumni engagement and development outreach.

### 4\. Third Party Recipients of Personal Information

* * *

In certain circumstances, UB shares limited personal information with third-party contractors and vendors providing specific services related to the University’s educational purpose. These relationships are generally subject to contract, requiring the third party’s legitimate interest in the User information which is only used as necessary to perform the third party’s contracted services.  Most of these relationships are related to the UB’s academic or IT services.

### 5\. Protection of Personal Information

* * *

UB uses substantive technical measures to safeguard and protect User personal information, including without limitation: firewalls, Secure Socket Layer communications and password protected systems.

### 6\. Questions or Concerns

* * *

If you have any questions or inquiries regarding this privacy policy or the manner in which UB processes User personal information, please contact us by email at ubprivacy@bridgeport.edu or by mail to the attention of the Privacy Policy Coordinator at the University of Bridgeport, 126 Park Ave, Bridgeport, CT 06604.

### 7\. Additional Resources

* * *

For more information regarding your data privacy rights, please see http://www.edugdpr.org (regarding General Data Protection Regulations) and https://www.ftc.gov/tips-advice/business-center/guidance/how-comply-privacy-consumer-financial-information-rule-gramm (regarding Gramm-Leach-Bliley Act).

### 8\. Amendments

* * *

The University may amend this Privacy Policy from time to time by posting the most recent version on its website.
